# **CRAIG JOHNSON**

(515) 422-3001 craigjo67@icloud.com craiginiowa.com

15058 Summit Dr Clive, Iowa 50325

## **PROFILE**

Web developer for the last 13 years, preceded by 15 years as a graphic artist and designer. A motivated self starter, adept at learning new languages and software. Experience in deadline-intensive environment of daily newspapers and client-driven environment of an advertising and marketing agency.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Developer, Gannett | USA TODAY Network — 2018-Present

Full-stack developer producing responsive web apps and pages for Gannett's newspaper properties. Specialize in reactive javascript frameworks such as Svelte and Vue, with experience in server languages like Node and GoLang, and design applications like Photoshop, Illustrator and Figma.

# **Developer & News Artist, Des Moines Register — 2004-2017**

Created and maintained news web apps for the Register and as part of Gannett's LDSN team. Helped build out WordPress-based registration for RAGBRAI, the Register's annual bike ride, and a WordPress-based admin and frontend for tracking presidential candidate visits to Iowa. Lead developer on The Wall, a Pulitzer Prize-winning project looking at the U.S.-Mexico border. Designed and produced interactive Flash graphics, including special projects and games. Created 3-D illustrations and animations for print and online. Researched, wrote and illustrated news graphics and packages for print.

# News Artist, Lexington Herald-Leader - 1999-2004

Created charts, maps, graphics and illustrations for daily newspaper.

# **Art Director, Trapp Communications - 1997-1999**

Designed marketing and advertising materials, including print ads, brochures and logo and identity systems for Lexington, Ky., marketing company.

#### **EDUCATION**

Iowa State University, Ames, IA — BA in Journalism, 1989

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS (SCSS, Bootstrap, Foundation), Javascript (Node, Express, Svelte, Vue, Angular 2, MapBox, D3.js); PHP, GoLang, Python; Photoshop, Illustrator, Cinema 4-D, Figma; Objective-C, Swift; WordPress, Google Cloud Platform, Google Apps Script.